# 你看 小豬
Look! Piggy
# 把小豬放下來了哦
We've let the piggy out.
# 你看
Look!
# 吃點米糠拌飯
Eat some rice and bran.
# 把它養胖一點
Let it be fatter.
# 現在都瘦啦
It's getting skinny now.
# 沒人跟它玩
Nobody plays with it.
# 它們兩個在幹架
They're having a fight.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 好不好吃
Does it taste good?
# 猛吃
It's eating fiercely.
# 吃得好過癮啊
It's eating so merrily.
# 是不是放出來爽一點 是不是
It's so much more fun to be out here, isn't it?
# 被關在裡面不舒服吧
Being shut off there just can't be pleasant.
# 不要打架行不行
Can't you just stop fighting?
# 一下就被那豬吃掉啦
The pig eats it up right away.
# 小豬 這裡長了一個
Piggy, here you have
# 又長了一個肉
you have one more piece of pork here.
# 誒 哎 哎 哎呀 站不穩
Eh? Ay, ay, aya! It's wobbling.
# 給它吃了點酒糟 它站不穩
I've given it some distillers grains. It's wobbling now.
# 每天都有酒糟吃 這個豬
It has distillers grains everyday, this pig.
# 豬都有點 吃得有點暈暈的
So the pig is, so it's now a bit dizzy.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 它理都不理我
It's not giving me any response at all.
# 天天給它吃酒糟
I give it distillers grains everyday.
# 吃得比較胖一點哦
Eat more and grow fatter.
# 很快 很快壯的哦
Soon, soon you'll be strong.
# 這條豬最少現在 至 至少六七
This pig is at least, now, at, at least three
# 額 六十斤左右
eh, around thirty kilograms.
# 一身肥膘
It's covered with fat.
# 本來打算跟它減減肥的
I originally planned to have it on diet.
# 算啦 現在豬都那麼貴
Forget it. Pork is so expensive these days.
# 現在快過年了哦
It will soon be the Chinese New Year.
# 準備殺一條豬來過年
We might kill one of the pigs for the New Year.
# 趁天氣好 搞點臘肉來
This excellent weather is the most suitable for making cured pork.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 你說我是
Do you think I should,
# 我是
I should,
# 殺你還是殺誰
kill you or whoever?
# 啊
Ah?
# 11條豬 你選
Eleven pigs. You choose!
# 你選到哪條
Which one do you choose?
# 你選哪條
Which one?
# 這種豬肉很好吃的
The pork from this kind of pigs tastes very good.
# 它那個瘦肉哇
The lean meat,
# 它那個瘦肉很香的哦
the aroma of the lean meat is exceptional.
# 脂肪的就 幾乎都沒有甚麼脂肪
And fat is, there's hardly any fat.
# 全是皮加肉
There's only skin and meat,
# 加骨頭
and bones.
# 排骨也很 很不錯的哦
The ribs are also, also not bad.
# 特別它 特別是它的那個
Especially, especially its
# 那個 那 那個腿 腿上的肉
its, I mean, its leg, the meat on its leg,
# 用來煲湯 特別好吃
can make really delicious soup.
# 耳朵 耳朵用來炒 炒辣椒
The ear, the ear can be fried with pepper.
# 爽歪歪喲
Cool!
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 要不要料酒
Do you want some cooking wine?
# 茅台料酒哦 要不要喝一點
It's Maotai cooking wine. Do you want some?
# 暈啦
It's dizzy.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 看我一眼哦
Give me a glance!
# 看都不看我一眼
It doesn't even deign to give me glance.